# Lysa Unku-Jones

07971 515151 | lysa.jones@googlemail.com 111A Moray Road, London N4 3LB https://wildelyssa.github.io

## **Profile**

I am a Front-End Web Developer with a passion for quality code and learning. I currently work freelance building stylish, functional, and responsive websites from concept to implementation. I focus on providing great user experience and following the best practices. I am a skilled communicator, consulting and collaborating with clients in order to bring their visions into a cohesive and practical design.

I have excellent skills in HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript and have experience building custom websites using Wordpress and PHP (including custom themes). I am active on GitHub, and regularly upload new and updated personal projects.

## Skills

Technical Skills	Personal Skills	
Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP	Excellent interpersonal and communication skills	
Version control: Git	Creativity, abstract thinking, and seeing the big	
Content Management: Wordpress	picture	
Libraries: Bootstrap, some experience of React	Reflective thinking and analytical skills	
API: Text-to-speech, Quotes, Jokes, Instagram, GoogleMaps, Screen capture	Working independently as well as with a team	
	Thorough and detail-oriented	

# **Work Experience**

## Web Developer (Contract): Lara Oz Therapies, London 2020 - Present

Created a website for Lara Oz Therapies, London from concept to production. The website is built using Wordpress, ACF and Contact Form 7. The client is evolving their business to focus on online presence and group work. Currently, I am working on developing the blog functionality that will be the client's primary tool for building their audience and promoting new services.

Technical Tasks	Other Responsibilities
<ul> <li>Fully custom theme (fully responsive and cross-browser)</li> <li>Optimised assets (logo, images)</li> <li>Contact Form with validation and ReCAPTCHA integration</li> <li>Google Maps integration (fully custom)</li> <li>SEO and Social Media Optimisation (in development)</li> <li>Blog (in development)</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>Brand guardianship: maintaining brand consistency and feel throughout the site.</li> <li>Assets and content management</li> <li>Configuring and maintaining hosting environment (LAMP)</li> <li>Providing support and problem solving</li> <li>Communicating at key stages</li> <li>Understanding needs of client and business</li> </ul>

## Freelance Web Developer: London 2020 – present

Using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Wordpress and PHP to produce stylish and functional websites. Consulting with clients, making suggestions where needed and managing client expectations. Working with APIs to integrate with required services. Understanding the needs of the client and the project. Communicating ideas in a clear and understandable way. Designing with a view to User Experience. Managing time and working to deadlines. Keeping up with industry standards and trends. Continually learning and developing skills and new ways of working.

#### Holistic Therapist: London 2014–2019

Providing personalised holistic treatments. Maintaining and updating a personal business website, blog, accounts and records. Email marketing campaigns, including designing HTML emails. Social Media marketing through Facebook, Instagram and LinkedIn. Organising and advertising events. Collaborating with colleagues, event organisers, spaces, and studios for workshops, events and talks.

#### Senior Stylist: Lucinda Ellery Hair Consultants Ltd, London 2010–2014

Providing hair replacement systems, extensions and solutions to hair loss. All aspects of hair styling including styling lessons and aftercare advice. Finding creative solutions and managing change in a fast-paced team environment.

## Junior Stylist, the Salon, Birmingham 2008–2010

Working as part of a small team providing all aspects of high quality hair styling. Managing own workload and supporting teammates when appropriate. Reception duties including scheduling and managing bookings, taking payments, answering queries via email and phone.

## Data Analyst/Health and Safety Officer, Atkins Global, Birmingham 2005–2008

Analysing datasets for Transport Planning and the Highways Agency. Working with Microsoft Excel, Access, Word to input and analyse data. Finding and analysing patterns and anomalies in data and conducting research into causes. Producing graphs and reports in Excel and using in-house software. Completing Health and Safety audits. Providing Health and Safety training and inductions. Maintaining accurate records.

## **Technical courses**

FreeCodeCamp	HTML, CSS, Responsive Development and Design
Zero To Mastery Academy	The Complete Web Developer, JavaScript Web Projects
Academind	JavaScript- The Complete Guide 2021 (beginner to advanced)
Udemy	Web Design for Web Developers
Codecademy	Learn CSS, Learn JavaScript, Web Developer Career Path

# **Formal Education**

New College, Telford, Shropshire				
Physics	A-Level	В		
Mathematics	A-Level	С		
History	A-Level	A		
Archaeology	AS-Level	В		
Wrockwardine Wood School, Telford, Shropshire				
History, Music, French	GCSE	A*		
English Literature, Chemistry	GCSE	A		
English Language, Biology, Physics, Maths, Graphics	GCSE	В		

References available on request